In this video I'd like
在这个视频中，我将(字幕翻译：中国海洋大学，孙中卫)
to tell you about the principle
介绍
components analysis algorithm.
主成分分析算法
And by the end of this
在视频的最后，
video you know to implement PCA for yourself.
你应该能独自使用主成分分析算法。
And use it reduce the dimension of your data.
同时，能够使用PCA对自己的数据进行降维。
Before applying PCA, there is
在使用PCA之前，
a data pre-processing step which you should always do.
将首先进行数据预处理。
Given the trading sets of the
给定一个交易例子的集合，
examples is important to
重要的步骤是
always perform mean normalization,
要总是执行均值标准化。
and then depending on your data,
依据你的数据，
maybe perform feature scaling as well.
大概也需要进行特征的缩放。
this is very similar to the
这是很相似的，
mean normalization and feature scaling
在均值标准化过程与特征缩放的过程之间
process that we have for supervised learning.
在我们已学习的监督学习中。
In fact it's exactly the
实际上，确实是
same procedure except that we're
相同过程，除了我们现在
doing it now to our unlabeled
对未标记数据做的，
data, X1 through Xm.
X1到Xm。
So for mean normalization we
对于均值标准化，
first compute the mean of
我们首先计算
each feature and then
每个特征的均值，
we replace each feature, X,
我们取代每个特征X用
with X minus its mean,
X减去它的均值。
and so this makes each feature
这将使每个特征
now have exactly zero mean
现在有个恰当的零均值。
The different features have very different scales.
不同的特征有非常不同的缩放。
So for example, if x1
例如，x1
is the size of a house, and
是房子的尺寸，
x2 is the number of bedrooms, to
x2是卧室的数量，
use our earlier example, we
对于我们先前的例子，
then also scale each feature
我们也可以缩放每个特征
to have a comparable range of values.
获取一个相对的价值范围。
And so, similar to what
相似于
we had with supervised learning,
我们之前的监督学习，
we would take x, i substitute
我们提取xi
j, that's the j feature
的第j个特征。
and so we would
所以我们能够
subtract of the mean,
减去均值。
now that's what we have on top, and then divide by sj.
想在对于我们上面做的，除以sj.
Here, sj is some measure of the beta values of feature j.  So, it could be the max minus
在这里，sj是特征j的beta值的一些测量值。所以，它是最大减去
min value, or more commonly,
最小值，或更普通的。
it is the standard deviation of
sj是一个特征j的偏差标准。
feature j. Having done
this sort of data pre-processing, here's what the PCA algorithm does.
做了数据预处理流程后，这是PCA算法做的。
We saw from the previous video
我们能从先前的视频中看到
that what PCA does is, it
PCA所做的，
tries to find a lower
它尝试着找到一个
dimensional sub-space onto which to
低维子空间，
project the data, so as
进行数据处理，
to minimize the squared projection
只为了最小化平方投影
errors, sum of the
误差，
squared projection errors, as the
最小化平方和投影误差，
square of the length of
随着这些蓝线所表示的
those blue lines that and so
的平方，
what we wanted to do specifically
我们想做的是
is find a vector, u1, which
找到一个向量，u1,
specifies that direction or
指定这个方向或者
in the 2D case we want
在2维中，我们
to find two vectors, u1 and
想找到2个向量，u1和
u2, to define this surface
u2,来定义这个表面，
onto which to project the data.
用于投射数据。
So, just as a
正如
quick reminder of what reducing
一个快速的提醒对于减少
the dimension of the data means,
数据均值的维数。
for this example on the
对左边的例子，
left we were given
我们给予
the examples xI, which are in r2.
西，在r2中。
And what we
我们
like to do is find
想找到
a set of numbers zI in
一个数据集合zi在r
r push to represent our data.
中代表我们的数据。
So that's what from reduction from 2D to 1D means.
所以我们的均值从2维降到1维。
So specifically by projecting
所以特别提醒
data onto this red line there.
把数据投射到红线上。
We need only one number to
我们仅需一个数字
specify the position of the points on the line.
来表示在线上的点的位置。
So i'm going to call that number
所以我们叫这个数字为
z or z1.
z或z1.
Z here  [xx] real number, so that's like a one dimensional vector.
Z是真实数字，以便像一个1维向量。
So z1 just refers to
所以z1仅涉及
the first component of this,
一个主成分，
you know, one by one matrix, or this one dimensional vector.
它是一个1：1矩阵，或是一个一维向量。
And so we need only
所以我们仅需要
one number to specify the position of a point.
一个数字来指明一个点的位置。
So if this example
所以如果这个例子
here was my example
是我的一个例子X1,
X1, then maybe that gets mapped here.
大概得到相应的映射。
And if this example was X2
如果这个例子是x2
maybe that example gets mapped
大概例子也得到映射。
And so this point
所以对应的点
here will be Z1
将是z1
and this point here will be
这个点对应的将是
Z2, and similarly we
z2,相似的
would have those other points
我们将有其他的点对于这些，
for These, maybe X3,
大概是x3,
X4, X5 get mapped to Z1, Z2, Z3.
x4,x5,得到映射z1,z2,和z3.
So What PCA has
所以PCA要做的是
to do is we need to
我们需要
come up with a way to compute two things.
想出一个方法计算两个事情。
One is to compute these vectors,
一个是计算这些向量
u1, and in this case u1 and u2.
例如u1,和在哪个事件中的u1和u2.
And the other is
另一个是
how do we compute these numbers,
如何来计算这些数字
Z. So on the
Z.所以
example on the left we're reducing the data from 2D to 1D.
在左边的例子汇总我们降维数据从2维到1维。
In the example on the right,
在右边的例子中，
we would be reducing data from
我们能降维数据从
3 dimensional as in
三维
r3, to zi, which is now two dimensional.
到zi,它是一个二维数据。
So these z vectors would now be two dimensional.
所以这些z向量现在将是二维的。
So it would be z1
所以它将是z1
z2 like so, and so
z2这样的，所以
we need to give away to compute
我们需要有方法计算
these new representations, the z1
这些新的模型代表，
and z2 of the data as well.
这些z1和z2的数据也一样。
So how do you compute all of these quantities?
所以你如何来计算所有的参数那？
It turns out that a mathematical
已经证明一个数学的
derivation, also the mathematical
推导，也就是数学的
proof, for what is
证明对于
the right value U1, U2, Z1,
U1，U2,Z1,Z2等是正确的。
Z2, and so on.
That mathematical proof is very
这个数学证明是非常
complicated and beyond the
复杂的，超出了
scope of the course.
课程的范围。
But once you've done  [xx] it
但是你已经做的，
turns out that the procedure
证明这个过程
to actually find the value
实际能够找到
of u1 that you want
你想要的u1值，
is not that hard, even though
这是不困难的，尽管
so that the mathematical proof that
这个数学证明
this value is the correct
这个值是正确的。
value is someone more
这个值有些人想更多
involved and more than i want to get into.
的涉及，超出想得到的i.
But let me just describe the
但让我描述
specific procedure that you
具体的过程，
have to implement in order
你想执行为了
to compute all of these
计算所有的
things, the vectors, u1, u2,
参数，向量u1,u2
the vector z.  Here's the procedure.
向量z,这是一个过程。
Let's say we want to reduce
我们想把
the data to n dimensions
n维的数据降到
to k dimension What we're
k维，
going to do is first
我们首先要做的
compute something called the
是计算
covariance matrix, and the covariance
协方差，这个协方差
matrix is commonly denoted by
通常用
this Greek alphabet which is
希腊字母表中
the capital Greek alphabet sigma.
的 sigma表示。
It's a bit unfortunate that the
不幸的是
Greek alphabet sigma looks exactly
这个希腊字母sigma看起来
like the summation symbols.
像一个求和标记。
So this is the
所以这里的
Greek alphabet Sigma is used
希腊字母Sigma被用来
to denote a matrix and this here is a summation symbol.
标记一个矩阵，在那里是一个求和标记。
So hopefully in these slides
所以希望在幻灯片
there won't be ambiguity about which
不要有模糊对于
is Sigma Matrix, the
Sigma 矩阵，
matrix, which is a
另一个是
summation symbol, and hopefully
求和标记，希望
it will be clear from context when
它能被区分从内容上，
I'm using each one.
当我们使用每一个的时候。
How do you compute this matrix
如何计算这个矩阵
let's say we want to
比如说我们想
store it in an octave variable
存储它到一个octave变量中，
variable called sigma.
变量叫sigma。
What we need to do is
我们需要做什么
compute something called the
来计算被叫做
eigenvectors of the matrix sigma.
矩阵sigma的特征向量。
And an octave, the way you
对于一个octave，你的方法
do that is you use this
是用这个
command, u s v equals
命令
s v d of sigma.
或公式来计算。
SVD, by the way, stands for singular value decomposition.
SVD代表奇异值分解，
This is a Much
这是一个更
more advanced single value composition.
加高级的单值组成。
It is much more advanced linear
它也是更加高级的线性
algebra than you actually need
代数比你实际需要
to know but now It turns out
知道的但结果是
that when sigma is equal
sigma等同
to matrix there is
矩阵，有几个
a few ways to compute these are
方法可以在高维向量中
high in vectors and If you
进行计算，如果你
are an expert in linear algebra
是一个专家在线性代数上，
and if you've heard of high in
如果你已经听过高维的
vectors before you may know
向量在你知道
that there is another octet function
有另一个叫I的octet函数，
called I, which can
它能够
also be used to compute the same thing.
被用来计算相同的事。
and It turns out that the
已经证明这个
SVD function and the
SVD函数和
I function it will give
这个I函数将给
you the same vectors, although SVD
你相同的向量，但SVD
is a little more numerically stable.
将更加具有数据稳定性。
So I tend to use SVD, although
所以我趋向于用SVD，尽管
I have a few friends that use
我有几个朋友用
the I function to do
I函数也能很好的做这些，
this as well but when you
很好的做这些，当你
apply this to a covariance matrix
用I函数求一个协方差矩阵
sigma it gives you the same thing.
sigma，给你的结果是相同。
This is because the covariance matrix
这是因为协方差矩阵
always satisfies a mathematical
总是满足一个数学
Property called symmetric positive definite
属性叫正定矩阵。
You really don't need to know
你不需要知道
what that means, but the SVD
他的含义，但这个SVD
and I-functions are different functions but
和I函数是不同的函数
when they are applied to a
当他们被运用到
covariance matrix which can
协方差矩阵时这被
be proved to always satisfy this
证明总是满足
mathematical property; they'll always give you the same thing.
这个数学属性；这两个函数给予相同的结果。
Okay, that was probably much more linear algebra than you needed to know.
好的，这大概将是更高深的线性代数比我们知道的。
In case none of that made sense, don't worry about it.
如果没有明白的话，不用担心。
All you need to know is that
你需要知道的
this system command you
这个系统命令，你能够
should implement in Octave.
用它在Octave。
And if you're implementing this in a
你也可以用它在
different language than Octave or MATLAB,
不同语言如Octave或MATLAB。
what you should do is find
我们应该做的是找到
the numerical linear algebra library
数值线性代数库
that can compute the SVD
能够计算 SVD
or singular value decomposition, and
或奇异值分解，
there are many such libraries for
有许多这样的库
probably all of the major programming languages.
对大多数的主要编程语言。
People can use that to
人们能够用这些来
compute the matrices u,
计算矩阵u，
s, and d of the covariance matrix sigma.
s,和协方差矩阵sigma d.
So just to fill
仅为了满足
in some more details, this covariance
一些细节，这个协方差
matrix sigma will be
矩阵sigma将
an n by n matrix.
是 N—N的矩阵。
And one way to see that
一个明白的方法是
is if you look at the definition
你能够看到定义
this is an n by 1
一个N-1的
vector and this
向量，
here I transpose is
另一个是
1 by N so the
1-N的，所以
product of these two things
这两个的结果
is going to be an N
是一个N-N
by N matrix.
的矩阵。
1xN transfers, 1xN, so
1-N 转移，1-N，所以
there's an NxN matrix and when
一个N-N的矩阵，当
we add up all of these you still
我们合计这些后，你还是
have an NxN matrix.
有一个N-N的矩阵。
And what the SVD outputs three
SVD输出的是三
matrices, u, s, and
个矩阵，u，s,和
v.  The thing you really need out of the SVD is the u matrix.
v. 你真的需要的SVD输出是u矩阵。
The u matrix will also be a NxN matrix.
这个 u矩阵也将是一个N-N的矩阵。
And if we look at the
我们看到的
columns of the U
u矩阵的列
matrix it turns
被证明：
out that the columns
u矩阵
of the U matrix will be
的列将是
exactly those vectors, u1,
这些向量， u1,
u2 and so on.
u2等。
So u, will be matrix.
所以u ,将是矩阵。
And if we want to reduce
如果我们想减
the data from n dimensions
少数据的维数从n维
down to k dimensions, then what
到k维。
we need to do is take the first k vectors.
我们需要做的是提取前k个向量。
that gives us u1 up
这将给我们u1
to uK which gives
到uK的向量，给了我们
us the K direction onto which
K个方向，我们想把数据
we want to project the data.
投射的方向。
the rest of the procedure from
这个剩余的过程是
this SVD numerical linear
这个SVD数值线性
algebra routine we get this
代数的程序，我们得到
matrix u.  We'll call
矩阵u. 我们称
these columns u1-uN.
这些列为u1-uN。
So, just to wrap up the
所以，为了结束这个
description of the rest of
剩余过程
the procedure, from the SVD
的描述，来自于SVD
numerical linear algebra routine we
数值线性代数程序，我们
get these matrices u, s,
得到这些矩阵u，s,
and d.  we're going
和d.我们将
to use the first K columns
用这个矩阵的前
of this matrix to get u1-uK.
K个列获取u1-uK的向量。
Now the other thing we need
现在我们需要做的其它事情
to is take my original
是获取我们的原始
data set, X which is
数据集，X这是一个
an RN And find a
RN值域。找到
lower dimensional representation Z, which
一个低维的代表Z,他是
is a R K for this data.
R K 对于这些数据。
So the way we're
所以，我们
going to do that is
将要做的是
take the first K Columns of the U matrix.
获取u矩阵的前K列。
Construct this matrix.
构建这个矩阵。
Stack up U1, U2 and
累计U1,U2等
so on up to U K in columns.
直到UK在列上。
It's really basically taking, you know,
你知道我们本质上是
this part of the matrix, the
获取矩阵的这部分，
first K columns of this matrix.
这个矩阵的前K列。
And so this is
所以这将获取
going to be an N
一个N-K
by K matrix.
的矩阵。
I'm going to give this matrix a name.
我将给予这个矩阵一个名字，
I'm going to call this matrix
我将叫这个矩阵为
U, subscript "reduce," sort
U，下标"reduce"，这是一类，
of a reduced version of the U matrix maybe.
U矩阵被降维的版本。
I'm going to use it to reduce the dimension of my data.
我将用它对我的数据降维。
And the way I'm going to compute Z is going
我将计算Z，将让
to let Z be equal to this
Z等于这个
U reduce matrix transpose times
U的降维矩阵转置相乘
X. Or alternatively, you know,
X.或者，你知道
to write down what this transpose means.
写下这个转置的意思。
When I take this transpose of
当我获取这个
this U matrix, what I'm
u矩阵的转置时，我将
going to end up with is these vectors now in rows.
在行上结束这些向量。
I have U1 transpose down to UK transpose.
我有U1转置到UK转置。
Then take that times X,
然后乘以X,
and that's how I get
这将让我
my vector Z. Just to
得到向量Z.为了
make sure that these dimensions make sense,
确定这些维数有意义，
this matrix here is going
这个矩阵将是
to be k by n
K-N的，
and x here is going
x是
to be n by 1
N-1,
and so the product
所以这个结果
here will be k by 1.
将是K-1的。
And so z is k
所以z是k
dimensional, is a k
维的，是一个k
dimensional vector, which is exactly
维向量，这是
what we wanted.
我们想要的。
And of course these x's here right, can
当然，这个x是正确的，
be Examples in our
将是例子在我们的
training set can be examples
训练集，也是例子
in our cross validation set, can be
在我们的交叉验证集中，
examples in our test set, and
也是例子在我们的测试集中，
for example if you know,
例如，如果你知道，
I wanted to take training example i,
我想得到训练集i,
I can write this as xi
我能够写这些作为xi,
XI and that's what will
XI 和，将给我们
give me ZI over there.
ZI是什么。
So, to summarize, here's the
所以，总而言之，这是
PCA algorithm on one slide.
幻灯片上的PCA算法。
After mean normalization, to ensure
进行均值归一化后，为确保
that every feature is zero mean
每一个特征都是零均值的，
and optional feature scaling which You
任选特征缩放，你
really should do feature scaling if
能够做特征的缩放，如果
your features take on very different ranges of values.
你的特征能够呈现不同范围的值。
After this pre-processing we compute
预处理完成之后，我们计算
the carrier matrix Sigma like
这个载体矩阵Sigma像
so by the
这个方法，
way if your data is
如果你的数据
given as a matrix
是被给予作为一个矩阵，
like hits if you have your
你有的
data Given in rows like this.
数据被给与在行中像这样。
If you have a matrix X
如果你有一个矩阵X，
which is your time trading sets
这是你的时间交易集
written in rows where x1
被写在行上是x1转置
transpose down to xm transpose,
到xm的转置。
this covariance matrix sigma actually has
这个协方差矩阵sigma 实际上有
a nice vectorizing implementation.
一个非常好的向量化实现。
You can implement in octave,
你能够执行在octave。
you can even run sigma equals 1
你能够甚至运行sigma等于
over m, times x,
1/m乘以x的转置,
which is this matrix up here,
这是这个矩阵放在哪。
transpose times x and
乘以x,
this simple expression, that's
这个简单的表达，这个
the vectorize implementation of how
向量化的实现，是如何计算
to compute the matrix sigma.
矩阵sigma。
I'm not going to prove that today.
今天，我将不证明它。
This is the correct vectorization whether you
正如你所知道的，这是一个正确的向量化，
want, you can either numerically test
你或者单独的数值测试
this on yourself by trying out an
它通过尝试octave。
octave and making sure that
或者确信
both this and this implementations
在它和它的实施中
give the same answers or you Can try to prove it yourself mathematically.
有相同的答案，或者你能够通过数学证明他。
Either way but this is the
无论怎么样，这是
correct vectorizing implementation, without compusing next
正确的向量化引用，不需要要质疑。
we can apply the SVD
我们能够运用SVD
routine to get u, s,
程序得到u，s,
and d. And then we
和d.我们
grab the first k
抓取
columns of the u
矩阵u的前k列，
matrix you reduce and
你所要降维到的，
finally this defines how
最终这个定义
we go from a feature
我们如何得到从一个特征
vector x to this
向量x到这
reduce dimension representation z. And
个降维的代表z.
similar to k Means
相似的k的意思，
if you're apply PCA, they way
如果你运用PCA，
you'd apply this is with vectors X and RN.
你也运用它到向量X和RN。
So, this is not done with X-0 1.
所以，这里xo不能为1.
So that was
这就是
the PCA algorithm.
PCA算法。
One thing I didn't do is
有件事情是我不能
give a mathematical proof that
给予一个数学的证明，
this There it actually give
这里它实际上
the projection of the data onto
给予数据的投射
the K dimensional subspace
到k维子空间
that actually
这实际
minimizes the square projection error Proof
是最小化投射平方的误差证明
of that is beyond the scope of this course.
超出了我们课程的学习范围。
Fortunately the PCA algorithm
幸运的是这个PCA算法
can be implemented in not
将不会被执行
too many lines of code.
用太多的代码。
and if you implement this in
如果你执行它在
octave or algorithm, you
太多或者算法中，你
actually get a very effective
实际能够得到一个非常有效
dimensionality reduction algorithm.
的降维算法。
So, that was the PCA algorithm.
所以，这就是PCA算法。
One thing I didn't do was
一个事情是我不能
give a mathematical proof that
给予一个数学上的证明，
the U1 and U2 and so
U1和U2等，
on and the Z and so
和Z等。
on you get out of this
你得出的这个过程
procedure is really the
是真实
choices that would minimize
的选着是最小化
these squared projection error.
平方投影误差。
Right, remember we said What
记住我说的，
PCA tries to do is try
PCA所做的是尝试找到
to find a surface or line
一个面或线
onto which to project the data
把数据投影到这个面或线上，
so as to minimize to square projection error.
以便于最小化平方投影误差。
So I didn't prove that this
我将不去证明它，
that, and the mathematical proof
这个数学的证明
of that is beyond the scope of this course.
超出了我们课程的范围。
But fortunately the PCA algorithm can
但幸运的是这个PCA算法能够
be implemented in not too many lines of octave code.
被执行不需要太多行octave代码。
And if you implement this,
如果你执行它 ，
this is actually what will
这实际上是我们将做的
work, or this will work well,
或这将做的很好，
and if you implement this algorithm,
如果你执行这个算法。
you get a very effective dimensionality reduction algorithm.
你将得到一个非常有效的降维算法。
That does do the right thing
这个做的一个正确的事情是
of minimizing this square projection error.
最小化平方投影误差。